Guide to the Edward Roe Eastman papers, 1923-1970.
Eastman, Edward Roe papers, 1923-1970.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Edward Roe Eastman papers, 1923-1970.
3105
Edward Roe Eastman, 1885-1970.
22 cubic ft.
Correspondence, pamphlets, clippings, speeches, radio talks, notes, scrapbooks, reports, books and surveys.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, pamphlets, and clippings concerning or authored by Edward Roe Eastman. Also, speeches, radio talks, notes, scrapbooks, reports, and surveys. Printed material includes New York Artificial Breeders Co-operator, 1948-1970; The Dairymen's League News (30 volumes); University of the State of New York, Regents Minutes (volumes 25-30); and other items concerning education.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Edward Roe Eastman was a writer, editor, educator, and farmer. He was born and raised in Berkshire, Tioga County, New York. He became a teacher and later a principal of schools in Interlaken, Richford, and Newark Valley. Eastman farmed for several years, and became the first county agent in Delaware County, New York, where he played an important part in forming the Dairymen's League Cooperative. He was editor of The Dairymen's League News from 1917-1922 and helped organize the State Conference Board of Farm Organizations as a vehicle for joint legislative action. He was the assistant county agricultural leader at the State College of Agriculture at Cornell University through World War I. In 1922, he became editor of the magazine American Agriculturalist until 1957, when he was named president emeritus of the publication. Eastman was president of the New York State Council on Rural Education, a member of the National Citizens Council for Better Schools, and helped establish the central school system for rural New York. He was a member and vice chancellor of the State Board of Regents, a trustee for both Ithaca College and Cornell University, and served as a counselor for Ithaca College students. He also authored several books, including Journey to Day Before Yesterday and Eastman's Chestnuts.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, pamphlets, and clippings concerning or authored by Edward Roe Eastman. Also, speeches, radio talks, notes, scrapbooks, reports, and surveys. Printed material includes New York Artificial Breeders Co-operator, 1948-1970; The Dairymen's League News (30 volumes); University of the State of New York, Regents Minutes (volumes 25-30); and other items concerning education.
Printing block of map for Eastman's 1946 novel "The Destroyers, a Historical Novel," about the Sullivan Campaign.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Eastman, Edward Roe, 1885-1970.; National Citizens Council for Better Schools.; New York State Council on Rural Education.; State Conference Board of Farm Organizations.
Titles:
American agriculturist.; The Dairymen's League news.; Eastman's chestnuts.; Journey to day before yesterday.; New York artificial breeders co-operator.; University of the State of New York regents minutes.
Subjects:
Education, Rural.; Agriculture--New York (State)--Delaware County.
Form and Genre Terms:
Surveys.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, pamphlets, and newsclippings, ca. 1967-1970 (Box 2)
- Correspondence and pamphlets, ca. 1920s, 1956-1970 (Box 3)
- Correspondence and pamphlets, ca. 1957-1964 (Box 4)
- Correspondence and pamphlets, ca. 1967-1968 (Box 5)
- Correspondence and pamphlets, ca. 1959-1968 (Box 6)
- Correspondence and pamphlets, ca. 1959-1967 (Box 7)
- Correspondence and pamphlets, ca. 1963-1968 (Box 8)
- Correspondence, ca. 1958-1969, 1920s (Box 9)
- Correspondence and pamphlets, ca. 1968-1969 (Box 10)
- Correspondence and pamphlets, ca. 1920s, 1950s, 1960s (Box 11)
- Correspondence and pamphlets, ca. 1959-1966 (Box 12)
- Correspondence and radio talks, 1931-1955 (Box 13)
- Correspondence, greeting cards, printed material, books by E.R. Eastman, writings, 1956-1969 (Box 14)
- Correspondence, speeches, writings, 1938-1971 (Box 15)
- Correspondence, writings, notes, 1950-1970 (Box 16)
- Correspondence, 1923-1965 (Box 17)
- Correspondence, reports, surveys, 1960-1968 (Box 18)
- Correspondence, radio talks, 1931-1970 (Box 19)
- New York Artificial Breeders Co-operator, 1948-1970 (Box 20)
- Scrapbooks, diplomas, plaques, awards/certificates, graduation hoods (Box 21)
- Scrapbooks, awards/certificates, medals/pins, greeting cards, printing block of map from "The Destroyers, a Historical Novel", books by Eastman (Box 22)